<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.0-c316 44.253921, Sun Oct 01 2006 17:08:23">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xap="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xap:ModifyDate>2009-04-30T14:09:43-04:00</xap:ModifyDate>
         <xap:CreateDate>2009-04-30T14:09:43-04:00</xap:CreateDate>
         <xap:MetadataDate>2009-04-30T14:09:43-04:00</xap:MetadataDate>
         <xap:CreatorTool>Adobe Acrobat 8.1</xap:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xapMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xapMM:DocumentID>uuid:c2b96ca1-eecb-bf4a-80f8-36114541faea</xapMM:DocumentID>
         <xapMM:InstanceID>uuid:6198475d-7b64-e145-9d85-d78904f81cf3</xapMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 8.1 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><bookmark-tree><bookmark title="20090428123813426_0001"><destination structID="LinkTarget_12"/></bookmark><bookmark title="20090428123813426_0002"><destination structID="LinkTarget_26"/></bookmark><bookmark title="20090428123813426_0003"><destination structID="LinkTarget_38"/></bookmark><bookmark title="20090428123813426_0004"><destination structID="LinkTarget_50"/></bookmark><bookmark title="20090428123813426_0005"><destination structID="LinkTarget_62"/></bookmark><bookmark title="20090428123813426_0006"><destination structID="LinkTarget_74"/></bookmark><bookmark title="20090428123813426_0007"><destination structID="LinkTarget_86"/></bookmark><bookmark title="20090428123813426_0008"><destination structID="LinkTarget_98"/></bookmark><bookmark title="20090428123813426_0009"><destination structID="LinkTarget_110"/></bookmark><bookmark title="20090428123813426_0010"><destination structID="LinkTarget_122"/></bookmark></bookmark-tree><P>A checklist of pseudo-historical novels before Sir Walter Scott's Waverley (1814). Sources: Corvey Collection (C); Tompkins, Popular Novel (T) and Buck, Vorgeschichte des historischen Romans (B): </P><L><LI><LI_Label>1. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1762 	Leland, Thomas, Longsword, Earl ofSalisbury. A Historical Romance (B) (T) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>2. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1764 Walpole, Horace, Castle of Otranto. A Gothic Story (B) (T) C: The Castle ofOtranto. A Story Translated by William Marshall, Gent. From the Original Italian of Onupterio Musalto, Canon ofthe Church ofSt. Nicholas at Otranto. Berlin: Himbourg, 1794. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>3. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1772 	Hutchinson, William, The Hermitage: a British Story. (T) </LI_Title></LI></L><P>4. 1773 	Barbauld, Anna Laetitia. Sir Bertrand. (B) (T) </P><L><LI><LI_Label>5. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1774 	Hull, Richard Plantagenet, A legendary Tale. (T) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>6. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1776 Bicknell, Alexander, History ofLady Anne Neville, Sister to the Great Earl ofWarwick; in which are interspersed Memoirs of that Nobleman and the Principal Characters of the Age in which she lived. (T) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>7. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1776 Bicknell, Alexander, History of the Prince of Wales, Commonly Termed the Black Prince, eldest son of Edward Ill, with a short view of the reigns of Edward II and EdwardIll, andasummaryAccount oftheInstitution oftheorder ofthegarter. (T) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>8. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1777 	Bicknell, Alexander, TheLife ofAlfredthe Great, King oftheAnglo-Saxons. (T) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>9. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1777 Reeve, Clara, The Old English Baron; The Champion of Freedom.&lt;!&gt; (B) (T: 1778: 'Champion of Virtue') </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>10. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1783 Roberts, R., Albert, Edward and Laura, The Hermit of Priestland: three legendary tales. (T) </LI_Title></LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>11. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1783-85 Lee, Sophia. The Recess (B) (T) C: The Recess; or, A Tale ofOther Times. London: T. Cadell, 1804, 3 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>12. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1786 	Miss Lee (transl.) &lt;d'Amaud&gt;, Warbeck. (B: anon.) (T) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>13. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1787 Fuller, Anne, Alan Fitz-Osborne. (B) (T) C: Alan Fitz-Osborne, An Historical Tale. London: Wilkins, 1787, 2nd ed., 2 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>14. 	1787 anon., William of Normandy. (B) C: William of Normandy. An Historical Novel. London: T. Axtell, 1787,2 vols. </P><P>15. 	1789 Fuller, Anne, The Son of Ethelwulfe.&lt;!&gt; (B) C: The Son of Ethelwolf: An Historical Tale. London: G. G. and J. Robinson, 1800,2 vols. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>16. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1789 Mrs. Radcliffe, Castles ofAthlin and Dunbayne. (T) C: Radcliffe, Ann, The Castles of Athlin and Dunbayne. A Highland Story. London: James Carpenter, 1799, 3rd ed. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>17. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1789 	Reeve, Clara, The Exiles; or, Memoires ofthe Count de Cronstadt. (T) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>18. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1789 White, James, Earl Strongbow. (B) Earl Strongbow or, The History ofRichard de Clare and the beautiful Geralda. (T) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>19. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1790 	Ballin, Miss, The Statue Room; an Historical Tale. (T) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>20. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1790 	White, James, John of Gaunt. (B) The Adventures ofJohn ofGaunt, Duke ofLancaster. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>(T) </P><L><LI><LI_Label>21. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1790 	anon., Historic Tales. (B) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>22. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1790 	Mackenzie, Mrs. A&lt;nna&gt; M&lt;aria&gt;, Montmouth. (T) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>23. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1791 	Fox, 1., Tancred (B) &lt;A Tale ofAncient Times. London: William Lane, 1791&gt; </LI_Title></LI></L><P>24. 1791 	White, James, The Adventures of King Richard Coeur-de-Lion. (B) (T) </P><L><LI><LI_Label>25. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1791 	anon., The Duchess ofYork. (B) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>26. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1791 	Mackenzie, Mrs. A&lt;nna&gt; M&lt;aria&gt;, Danish Massacre. (T) </LI_Title></LI></L><P>27. 	1791 c: Siddons, Henry, William Wallace: or, The Highlarui Hero. A Tale Fouruied on Historical Facts. London: Wilkie, 1791,2 vols. </P><P>28. 1792 	Brydges, Egerton, Mary de Clifford. (T) </P><P>29. 	1792 Knight, Ellis Cornelia, Marcus Flaminius; or, a View of the Military, Political, arui SocialLife ofthe Romans:InaSeries ofLettersfromayoungPatriciantohisfriend, in the year 762 from the Fouruiation ofRome, to the year 769. (T) </P><P>30. 1792 	Tomlins, &lt;Eliza&gt; Sophia, Memoirs ofa Baroness. (T) </P><L><LI><LI_Label>31. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1793 anon., The Minstrel. (B) The Minstrel, or Anecdotes ofDistinguished Personages in the Fifteenth Century. (T) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>32. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1793 	Reeve, Clara, Sir Roger de Clarendon. (B) Memoirs ofSir Roger de Clareruion. (T) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>33. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1793 C: &lt;Walker, George&gt;, The Romance of the Cavern; or, The History of Fitz-Henry and James. London: William Lane, 1793,2 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>34. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1794 Cullen, Stephen, The Haunted Priory. (B) C: The Haunted Priory; Or, The Fortunes of the House ofRayo. A Romance. Fouruied partly on Historical Facts. Dublin: W. Jones, 1794. Lonson: Newman, 1832, 2 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>35. 1794 	C: anon., Edward de Courcy. An Ancient Fragment. London: W. Lane, 1794, 2 vols. </P><P>36. 	1794 Mrs. Radcliffe, Mysteries of Udolpho. (T) C: Radcliffe, Ann, The Mysteries of Udolpho. A Romance interspersed with some pieces of poetry. London: G.G. and 1. Robinson, 4th ed., 1799. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>37. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1794 	Walker, George, The Haunted Castle. (B) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>38. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1795 	anon., Arville Castle. (B) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>39. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1795 anon., The Duke of Clarence. (B) C: &lt;Foster, Mrs. E. M.&gt;, The Duke ofClarence, An Historical Novel. London: A. K. Newman &amp; Co., 1795,4 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>40. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1795 Landell&lt;!&gt;, Sarah, Manfredi, Baron of St. Osmond.&lt;!&gt; (B) C: &lt;Lansdell, Sarah&gt;, Manfredi, Baron St. Osmorui. An old English Romance. London: William Lane, 1796, 2 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>41. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1795 	Mackenzie, A&lt;nna&gt; M&lt;aria&gt;, Mysteries Elucidated. (T) </LI_Title></LI></L><P>42. 1795 	anon., Mountford Castle. (B) </P><L><LI><LI_Label>43. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1795 Warner, Richard, Netley Abbey. (B) C: &lt;Warner, Richard&gt;, Netley Abbey. A Gothic Story. Southampton: Skelton, 1795, 2 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>44. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1796 C: Bonhote, Elizabeth, Bungay Castle: A Novel. London: Lane, 1796, 2 vols. cf. (T) 1797 </LI_Title></LI></L><P>45. 	1796 Cullen, Stephen, The Castle ofInchvally. (B) C: The Castle ofInchvally, a Tale, alas! Too true. London: 1. Bell, 1796,3 vols. </P><P>46. 	1796 C: Kelly, &lt;lsabella&gt;, The Ruins of Avondale Priory. A Novel. London: William Lane, 1796, 3 vols. </P><P>47. 1796 	Mackenzie, A&lt;nna&gt; M&lt;aria&gt;, The Neapolitan, or, The Test ofIntegrity (T) </P><L><LI><LI_Label>48. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1796 C: anon., Memoirs ofthe Ancient House ofClarendon. A Novel. London: William Lane, 1796, 3 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>49. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1796 C: &lt;Musgrave, Agnes&gt;, Cicely, or the Rose of Raby. An Historical Novel. London: William Lane, 1796, 2nd ed., 4 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>50. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1796 C: Sherwood, Martha, The Traditions: a Legendary Tale. London: Lane, 1796, 2nd ed., 2 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>51. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1797 	Bonhote, Mrs., Bungay Castle. (T) cf. (C) 1796 </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>52. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>C: 1797 &lt;Moore, George&gt;, Grasville Abbey. A Romance. London: G. G. and J. Robinson, 1797, 3 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>53. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1797 C: &lt;Musgrave, Agnes&gt;, Edmund of the Forest. An historical Novel. By the author of 'Cicely, or the Rose of Raby'. London: William Lane, 1797,4 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>54. 	1798 C: &lt;Broster, John&gt;, The Castle of Beeston, or, Randolph, Earl of Chester. An Historical Romance. London: Faulder, 1798. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>55. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1798 	Drake, Nathan, Henry Fitzowen. (B) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>56. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1798 	C: anon., Godfrey de Hastings, a Romance. London: William Lane, 1798,3 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>57. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1798 	anon., The Knights. (B) </LI_Title></LI></L><P>58. 	1799 C: anon., Azalais and Aimar. A Provencal History of the Thirteenth Century, from an ancient Manuscript. London: &lt;William Lane &gt;, 1799. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>59. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1799 C: Mrs. Barnby, The Rock; Or Alfred and Anna. A Scottish Tale. London: Crosby &amp; Letterman, 1799, 2nd ed., 2 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>60. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1799 C: anon., Battleridge, an Historical Tale, founded on Facts. By a Lady of Quality. London: Cawthorn, 1799,2 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>61. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1799 C: &lt;Curties&gt;, T. J. Horsley, Ethelwina or the House of Fitz-Auburne. A Romance of Former Times. London: Lane, 1799, 3vols. cf. (B) 1802 </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>62. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1799 Godwin, William, St. Leon. (B) (T: 1800) C: 1800 St. Leon: A Tale of the SixLeenth Century. London: G.G. &amp; 1. Robinson, 1800, 2nd ed., 4 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>63. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1799 	Ireland, William Henry, The Abbess. (B) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>64. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1799 anon., A Northumbrian Tale. (B) (T) C: A Northumbrian Tale. Written by a Lady. London: Debrett, 1799. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>65. 	1799 C: &lt;Patrick, Mrs. F. C.&gt;, The Jesuit; Or, The History ofAnthony Babington, Esq. An Historical Novel. Bath: Cruttwell, 1799,3 vols. </P><P>66. 	1799 C: Rowson, &lt;Susanna Haswell&gt;, Reuben and Rachel; or Tales of Old Times. A Novel. London: Lane, 1799, 2 vols. </P><P>67. 	1799 C: &lt;Sands, James&gt;, Count di Novini; or The Confederate Chartusians. A Neapolitan Tale. London: G.G. &amp; 1. Robinson, 1799,3 vols. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>68. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1799 C: anon., The Witch and the Maid of Honour. London: Printed for the author, 1799,2 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>69. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1799 C: West, Jane, A Tale of the Times. By the author of 'A Gossip's Story'. London: T.N. Longman and O. Rees, 1799, 2nd ed., 3 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>70. 	1800 C: &lt;Craik, Helen&gt;, Henry of Northumberland; or the Hermit's Cell. A Tale of the Fifteenth Century. London: W. Lane, 1800, 3 vols. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>71. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1800 	C: Mrs. Croffts, Ankerwick Castle. A Novel. London: William Lane, 1800,4 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>72. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1800 C: &lt;Du Bois, Edward &gt;, St. Godwin: A Tale of the Sixteenth, Seventeenth, and Eighteenth Centuries, by Count Reginald De St. Leon. London: Wright, 1800, 2nd ed. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>73. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1800 C: &lt;Foster, E. M.&gt;, Jaquelina of Hainault, An Historical Novel. By the Author of 'The Duke of Clarence' &lt;1795&gt;. London: Lane, 1800, 2nd ed., 3 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>74. 	1800 C: Graglia, G&lt;iuseppe&gt; A., The Castle ofEridan; Or, The Entertaining and Surprising History of the Valiant Don Alvares, and the Beautiful Eugenia, Duchess of Savoy. </P><P>London: Hurst &amp; Baldwin, 1800. </P><P>75. 	1800 C: Ireland, &lt;Samuel&gt; W&lt;illiarn&gt; H&lt;enry&gt;, Rimualdo, Or, The Castle of Badajos. A Romance. London: Longman and Rees, 1800,4 vols. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>76. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1800 Kendall, A., Tales of the Abbey. (B) C: Tales of the Abbey; Founded on Historical Facts. London: H. D. Symonds, 1800,3 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>77. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1800 anon., The Lord of Hardivyle. (B) C: The Lord of Hardivyle, an Historical Legend of the Fourteenth Century. London: W. Treppass, 1800. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>78. 	1800 C: Mackenzie, Anna Maria, Feudal Events; or, Days of Yore. An Ancient Story. London: Lane, 1800,2 vols. (Tompkins, p. 237, only mentions the title without author and date of publication.) </P><P>79. 	1800 C: anon., Midsummer Eve, Or The Country Wake. A Tale of the Sixteenth Century. London: Mawman, 1800,2 vols. cf. (B) 1801 </P><P>80. 1800 	anon., Montrose. (B) </P><P>81. 	1800 anon., The Spirit of Turretville. (B) C: The Spirit of Turretville; Or, The Mysterious Resemblance. A Romance ofthe Twelfth Century. London: Dutton, 1800,2 vols. </P><P>82. 	1801 C: Curties, T. 1. Horsley, Ancient Records,' Or, The Abbey of Saint Oswythe, A Romance. London: William Lane, 1801,4 vols. </P><P>83. 	1801 Helme, Elizabeth, St. Margaret's Cave. (B) C: St. Margaret's Cave: or, The Nun's story. An Ancient Legend. London: Earle &amp; Hemet, 1801,4 vols. </P><P>84. 	1801 Kidderslaw, Johanson &lt;i.e. Mackenzie, Anna Maria&gt;, Swedish Mysteries, or, The Hero ofthe Mines. London: William Lane, 1801,3 vols. </P><P>85. 1801 	anon., Midsummer Eve. (B) cf. (C) 1800 </P><L><LI><LI_Label>86. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1801 C: Smith, Maria Lavinia, The Fugitive of the Forest. A Romance. London: William Lane, 1801,2 vols. bound as 1. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>87. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1801 	C: anon., St. Mary's Abbey. Chelmsford: printed for the author, 1801,2 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>88. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1802 C: anon., The Castle of Caithness. A Romance of the Thirteenth Century. ByF.H. P. London: Lane &amp; Newman, 1802, 2 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>89. 1802 	anon., Count Roderic's Castle. (B) </P><P>90. 	1802 C: Curties, T. J. Horsley, The Scottish Legend, or The Isle of Saint Clothair. A Romance. London: William Lane, 1802,4 vols. </P><P>91. 	1802 C: Hasworth, H. H., The Lady ofthe Cave; Or, Mysteries ofthe Fourteenth Century. An Historical Romance. London: Lane &amp; Newman, 1802,3 vols. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>92. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1802 	Horsley-Curties, J. T., Ethelwina. (B) cf. (C) 1799 Curties </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>93. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1802 Kelly, Isabella, The Baron's DaughJer. (B) C: The Baron's DaughJer: A Gothic Romance. London: Lane, Newman and Co., 1805, 2nd ed., 4 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>94. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1802 C: Lyttleton, M., Isabel, or, The Orphan of Valdarno, a Florentine Romance. London: Lane, 1802,3 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>95. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1802 Mackenzie, A. M., Martin and Mansfeldt; Or, The Romance of Franconia. (T) C: Mackenzie, Anna M.&lt;aria&gt;, Martin and Mansfeldt,' Or, The Romance of Franconia. London: Lane and Newman, 1802, 3 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>96. 	1802 C: Melville, Theodore, The White Knight, Or, The Monastery of Morne. A Romance. London: Crosby and Letterman, 1802, 3 vols. </P><P>97. 	1802 Millikin, Anna, Plantagenet. (B) C: Plantagenet; or, Secrets of the House ofAnjou; a Tale ofthe Twelfth Century. Cork: Connor, 1802,2 vols. </P><P>98. 	1802 Parker, Mary Elizabeth, Alfred. (B) C: Alfred, or the Adventures of the Knight of the Castle. A Novel. London: Apollo Press, 1802,3 vols. </P><Table><TR><TD>99. </TD><TD>1802 </TD><TD>Radcliffe, Ann, Gaston de Blondeville. (published in 1826) (f) C: Gaston de </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Blondeville, or The Court of Henry III, Keeping festival in Ardenne. A Romance. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>London: Henry Colburn, 1826,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>100. </TD><TD>1802 </TD><TD>Strutt, Joseph, Queenhoo-Hall. (published in 1808) (B) C: &lt;Edited by Sir Walter </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Scott&gt;, Queenhoo-Hall, A Romance: and Ancient Times, a Drama. London: John </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Murray, 1808,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>101. </TD><TD>1803 </TD><TD>C: anon., The Convent ofSt. Michael. A Tale: Taken from a German Manuscript ofthe </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Seventeenth Century. London: Hurst, 1803,2 vols. bound as 1. </TD></TR><TR><TD>102. </TD><TD>1803 </TD><TD>C: Helme, Elizabeth, St. Clair of the Isles; Or, the Outlaws of Barra. A Scottish </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Tradition. London: Longman and Rees, 1803,4 vols. cf. (B) 1804 </TD></TR><TR><TD>103. </TD><TD>1803 </TD><TD>C: Kramer, Prof. (trans!.) &lt;C.B.E. Naubert&gt;, Walter de Monbary, Grand Master of the </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Knights Templars. An Historical Romance. From the German of Professor Kramer. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>London: Lane and Newman, 1803, 4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>104. </TD><TD>1803 </TD><TD>Porter, Jane, Thaddeus of Warsaw. (B) C: Thaddeus ofWarsaw. London: Longman and </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Rees, 1803,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>105. </TD><TD>1803 </TD><TD>C: &lt;Singer, ...&gt;, Edwin, or the Heir ofAe/la. An Historical Romance. By the author of </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>'The Wanderer of the Alps'and 'The Mystical Castle'. London: Lane, Newman and </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Co., 1803, 3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>106. </TD><TD>1803 </TD><TD>C: Stael, Madame de &lt;Anne Louise Germaine de Stael-Holstein&gt;, Margret of </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Strafford, An Historical Romance: Interspersed with Several Anecdotes of the Reign of </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Charles II. And Other Memorials Relative to the Revolution. London: Hughes, 1803, 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>107. </TD><TD>1804 </TD><TD>C: Barnby, Mrs., (transl.) Kerwald Castle, Or, Memoirs of the Marquis de Solanges. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Translated from the French, by Mrs. Barnby. London: Lane, Newman and Co., 1804,2 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>108. </TD><TD>1804 </TD><TD>C: anon., Black Agnes; Or, The Defence ofDunbar by Agnes, Countess ofMarch, in the </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Year 1388. London: F.C and 1. Rivington, 1804. [in verse and prose, no novel] </TD></TR><TR><TD>109. </TD><TD>1804 </TD><TD>C: Canton, John, Alvar and Seraphina, or The Troubles of Murcia; An Historic </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Romance. London: Lane, Newman and Co., 1804,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>110. </TD><TD>1804 </TD><TD>C: anon., The Castle ofCaranza. A Romance. London: Lane, Newman and Co., 1804,2 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>111. </TD><TD>1804 </TD><TD>C: Curties, T. 1. Horsley, The Watch Tower, or The Sons of Ulthona. An Historic </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Romance. London: Brebtford for P. Norbury, 1804, 5 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>112. </TD><TD>1804 </TD><TD>Good&lt;!&gt;, Mrs. V. R., Sherwood Forest. (B) C: Gooch, &lt;Elizabeth Sarah&gt; Villa-Real, </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Sherwood Forest, or Northern Adventurers. A Novel. London: S. Highley, 1804,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>113. </TD><TD>1804 </TD><TD>Helme, Elizabeth, St. Clair ofthe Isles. (B) cf. (C) 1803 </TD></TR><TR><TD>114. </TD><TD>1804 </TD><TD>Mosse, Henrietta R., A Peep at our Ancestors. (B) C: A Peep at our Ancestors, An </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Historical Romance. London: Lane, Newman and Co., 1807,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>115. </TD><TD>1804 </TD><TD>C: Mosse, Henrietta Rouviere, Lussington Abbey. A Novel. London: Lane, Newman </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>and Co., 1804,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>116. </TD><TD>1804 </TD><TD>Murray, Hugh, The Swiss Emigrants. (B) C: The Swiss Emigrants; A Tale. London: </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Longman and Rees, 1804. </TD></TR><TR><TD>117. </TD><TD>1804 </TD><TD>C: Robertson, &lt;Eliza F.&gt;, Destiny; Or, Family Occurrences of the House of </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Derwentwater; An Interesting Narrative, including the Life of the Author. London: </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Burton, 1804, 2nd ed., 2 vols. bound as 1. </TD></TR></Table><Table><TR><TD>118. </TD><TD>1805 </TD><TD>c: anon., Edmond Ironside; Or, The Cave of Osmer; A Legend of the Ninth Century. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>London: Hughe's, 1805,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>119. </TD><TD>1805 </TD><TD>Helme, Elizabeth, The Pilgrim of the Cross. (B) C: The Pilgrim of the Cross; Or, The </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Chronicles of Christabelle de Mowbray. An Ancient Legend. Brentford: P. Norbury, </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>1805,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>120. </TD><TD>1805 </TD><TD>Ireland, William Henry, Gondez the Monk. (B) C: Gondez, the Monk. A Romance of the </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Thirteenth Century. London: Earle, 1805,4 vols., 4 bound as 2. </TD></TR><TR><TD>121. </TD><TD>1805 </TD><TD>Isaacs, Mrs., Glenmore Abbey; Or, The Lady of the Rock. A Novel. London: Lane, </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Newman and Co., 1805,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>122. </TD><TD>1805 </TD><TD>Lathom, Francis, The Fatal Vow. (B) C: The Fatal Vow; Or, St. Michael's Monastery. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>A Romance. London: Crosby and Co., 1805,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>123. </TD><TD>1805 </TD><TD>C: Lyttleton, M., Fiesco, Count of Lavagne. An Historical Novel. London: Lane and </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Newman, 1805,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>124. </TD><TD>1805 </TD><TD>Millikin, Anna. The Rival Chiefs. (B) C: The Rival Chiefs; or, the Battle of Mere. A </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Tale ofAncient Times. London: Lane, Newman and Co., 1805. </TD></TR><TR><TD>125. </TD><TD>1805 </TD><TD>C: Morley, G.T., Deeds ofDarkness; Or, The Unnatural Uncle. A Tale ofthe Sixteenth </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Century; including Interesting Memoirs, Founded on Facts. London: Tipper and </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Richards, 1805,2 vols, 2 bound as 1. </TD></TR><TR><TD>126. </TD><TD>1805 </TD><TD>Rice. Mrs., Monteith. (B) C: Monteith; A Novel, Founded on Scottish History. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Gainsborough: H. Mozley, 1805,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>127. </TD><TD>1805 </TD><TD>C: Williams, William Frederick, The Witcheries of Craig Istaf. London: Lane, </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Newman, and Co., 1805,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>·128. </TD><TD>1806 </TD><TD>Armstrong, Leslie, The Anglo-Saxons. (B) C: The Anglo-Saxons,' Or, The Court of </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Ethelwulph. London: Lane, Newman, 1806, 4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>129. </TD><TD>1806 </TD><TD>C: Dacre, Charlotte, ZofIoya; or, The Moor: A Romance of the Fifteenth Century. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>London: Longman, Hurst, Rees and Orme, 1806,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>130. </TD><TD>1806 </TD><TD>C: anon., Dellingborough Castle; or, The Mysterious Recluse. A Novel. London: Lane, </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Newman and Co., 1806,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>131. </TD><TD>1806 </TD><TD>C: anon., Glencore Tower; or, The Feuds of Scotland. A Legend of the Thirteenth </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Century. London: Lane, Newman &amp; Co., 2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>132. </TD><TD>1806 </TD><TD>C: Harvey, Jane, The Castle ofTynemouth. A Tale. London: Longman, Hurst, Rees and </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Orme, 1806,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>133. </TD><TD>1806 </TD><TD>Horsley-Curties, IT., St. Botolph's Priory. (B) C: Curties, T. 1. Horsley, St. Botolph's </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Priory; or the Sable Mask. An Historic Romance. London: Hughes, 1806,5 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>134. </TD><TD>1806 </TD><TD>C: Lake, Eliza, The Wheel of Fortune. A Novel. London: FJ. Hughes, 1806,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>135. </TD><TD>1806 </TD><TD>Lathom, Francis, The Mysterious Freebooter. (B) C: The Mysterious Freebooter; Or, </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>The Days ofQueen Bess, A Romance. London: Lane, Newman and Co., 1806,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>136. </TD><TD>1807 </TD><TD>C: anon., Baron de Falkenheim. A German Tale of the SixJeenth Century. London: </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Lane, Newman and CO.,1807, 2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>137. </TD><TD>1807 </TD><TD>C: Ireland, W&lt;illiam&gt; H&lt;enry&gt;, The Catholic. An Historical Romance. London: W. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Earle, 1807, 3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>138. </TD><TD>1807 </TD><TD>C: anon., Mandeville Castle; Or, The Two Elinors , by the author of 'Louisa, the orphan </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>of Lenox Abbey', London: Booth, 1807,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>139. </TD><TD>1807 </TD><TD>C: Moraes, Francisco de, Palmerin of England. Corrected by Robert Southey from the </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Original Portuguese. London: Longman, Hurst, Rees and Orme, 1807,4 vols. </TD></TR></Table><Table><TR><TD>140. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>c: anon., The Baron de Courcy; or Reading Abbey. A Legendary Tale. London: 1. F. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Hughes, 1808, 2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>141. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>C: Bouverie, Sophia, St. Justine, or The Hour of Trial. A Romance. London: FJ. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Hughes, 1808, 3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>142. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>C: Bouverie, Sophia, Lord Hubert of Arundel. A Romance. &lt;By the&gt; Author of 'St. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Justine, or The Hour of Trial'. London: FJ. Hughes, 1808,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>143. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>C: Bradshaw, Mary Anne Cavendish, Memoirs of Maria, Countess d'Alva. London: </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Miller, 1808, 2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>144. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>C: Dallas, Robert Charles, The Knights: Tales Illustrative of the Marvellous. London: </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Longman, Hurst, Reeve and Orme, 1808,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>145. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>Maxwell, C., Alfred ofNormandy. (B) C: Maxwell, Caroline, Alfred ofNormandy: or, </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>the Ruby Cross. An Historical Romance. London: A. Seale, 1808,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>146. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>Maxwell, C., Lionel. (B) C: Maxwell, Caroline, Lionel; or, The Impenetrable </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Command. An historical romance. London: Lane, Newman and Co., 1808,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>147. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>C: anon., The Monks and the Robbers. A Tale of the Fifteenth Century. London: G. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Robinson, 1808, 2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>148. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>Mosse, Henrietta, The Old English Baronet. &lt;I&gt; (B) C: Mosse, Henrietta Rouviere, The </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Old Irish Baronet, or, Manners of my Country, A Novel. London: Lane, Newman and </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Co., 1808,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>149. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>C: Musgrave, Agnes, William de Montfort; or, The Sicilian Heiresses. London: </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Richards, 1808,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>150. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>C: anon., Mystery upon Mystery: A Tale of Earlier Times.: By the author of the 'Baron </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>de Falkenheim'. London: Lane, Newman and Co., 1808,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>151. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>C: anon., Newminster Abbey, or the Daughter of o'More. A Novel, Founded on Facts,' </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>and Interspersed with Original Poetry, and Picturesque and Faithful Sketches of </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Various countries. London: J.F. Hughes, 1808,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>152. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>C: anon., The Ring and the Well, or, The Grecian Princess. A Romance. London: </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Longman, Hurst, Rees, and Orme, 1808,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>153. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>C: anon., Royal Legend. A Tale. London: Wilson, 1808,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>154. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>C: anon., Saint Hilary, the Crusader. A Romantic Legend. London: FJ. Hughes, 1808, </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>155. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>C: &lt;Savile de Starck, Henry of Layton, F.&gt;. Bertrand; or Memoirs of a Northwnbrian </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Nobleman in the Seventeenth Century, written by himself. London: Lane, Newman, and </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Co., 1808,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>156. </TD><TD>1808 </TD><TD>C: &lt;Sykes, S.&gt;. Margiana,' or, Widdrington Tower. A Tale of the Fifteenth century. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>London: Lane, Newman and Co., 1808,5 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>157. </TD><TD>1809 </TD><TD>C: anon., The Banks ofthe Carron, or the Towers ofLothian; A Scottish Legend. By the </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Author of 'The Two Pilgrims'. London: F. 1. Hughes, 1809,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>158. </TD><TD>1809 </TD><TD>C: anon., The Chamber of Death, Or, The Fate of Rosario. An Historical Romance of </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>the Sixteenth Century. By Orlando, Author of 'A Summer by the Sea'. London: AX. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Newman and Co., 1809, 2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>159. </TD><TD>1809 </TD><TD>C: Cumberland, Richard, John de Lancaster. A Novel. London: Lackington, Allen and </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Co., 1809, 2nd ed., 3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>160. </TD><TD>1809 </TD><TD>C: Hanway, &lt;Mary Ann&gt;, Falconbridge Abbey. A Devonshire Story. London: Lane, </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Newman, and Co., 1809,5 vols. </TD></TR></Table><P>161. 	1809 c: Lathom, Francis, The Romance ofthe Hebrides; Or, Wonders Never Cease! London: AX. Newman and Co., 1809, 3 vols. </P><P>162. 1809 	Mackenzie, A&lt;nna&gt; M&lt;aria&gt;, The Irish Guardian; or Errors ofEccentricity. (f) </P><L><LI><LI_Label>163. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1809 C: &lt;Meeke, Mary&gt;, Laughton Priory. A Novel. By Gabrielli, Author of Mysterious Wife, Mysterious Husband, etc. London: A.K. Newman and Co., 1809,4 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>164. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1809 C: Melville, Theodore, The Irish Chieftain, and his family. A Romance. London: Lane, Newman, and Co., 1809,4 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>165. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1809 C:, anon., Old Times Revived; A Romantic Story of the Ninth Age; With Parallels of Characters and Events of the 18. and 19. Centuries. By Egestas. London: Cawthorn, 1809, 4 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>166. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1809 Palmer, Alicia Tindal, The Husband and the Lover. (B) C: The Husband and the Lover; An Historical and Moral Romance. London: Lackington, Allen and Co., 1809,3 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>167. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1809 Porter, Anna Maria, Don Sebastian. (B) C: Don Sebastian, or The House of Braganza. An Historical Romance. London: Longman, Hurst, Rees, and Grme, 1809,4 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>168. 	1809 Wilmot, R. H., Scenes in Feudal Times. (B) C: Scenes in Feudal Times. A romance. London: G. Robinson, 1809,4 vols. </P><P>169. 	1810 Agg, John, McDermot. (B) C: MacDermot, or, The Irish Chieftain, A Romance intended as a companion to the Scottish Chiefs. London: George Shade, 1810,3 vols. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>170. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1810 anonym. Anne ofBrittany. (B) C: Anne ofBrittany; An Historical Romance. London: C. Craddock &amp; W. Joy, 1810,3 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>171. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1810 Appleton, Elizabeth, Edgar. (B) C: Edgar: A National Tale. London: Henry Colburn, 1816,3 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>172. 	1810 Bradshaw, Mary Anne Cavendish, Ferdinand and Ordella (B) C: Ferdinand and Ordella. A Russian Story; with Authentic Anecdotes of the russian Court After the Demise ofPeter the Great; to which is added, a prefatory Address to the Satirist, upon Patrons and Dedications, Reformers and Reformations. By Priscilla Parlante &lt;Mary Anne Cavendish-Bradshaw&gt;. London: Samuel Tipper, 1810,2 vols. </P><P>173. 	1810 Houghton, Mary, The Mysteries of the Forest. (B) C: The Mysteries of the Forest. A Romance. London: A.K. Newman, 1810, 2nd ed., 3 vols. </P><P>174. 	1810 C: anon., The House ofLancaster; Or, The Story ofA. P. Thomas. An Historical Nove/. London: FJ. Hughes, 1810,2 vols. </P><P>175. 	1810 C: Jones, Evan, The Bard, or The Towers ofMorven, A Legendary Tale. London: A.K. Newman and Co., 1810. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>176. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1810 C: &lt;Maturin, Charles Robert&gt;, The Avenger; or The Sicilian Vespers: A Romance of the Thirteenth Century, not inapplicable to the nineteenth. London: 1.J. Stockdale, 1810, 3 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>177. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1810 C: Montalbion, Kate, The Spanish Lady, and the Norman Knight. A Romance of the Eleventh Century. London: FJ. Hughes, 1810,2 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>178. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1810 Porter, Jane The Scottish Chiefs. (B) C: The Scottish Chiefs. A Romance. London: Longman, Rees, Hurst and Grme, 1810,5 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>179. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1810 C: St. Hilaire, Bridget, The Priory ofSt. Mary. A Romance Founded on Days of Old. London: R. Ryan, 1810, 2nd ed., 4 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>180. 	1811 Agg, John,_ Edwy and Egilva. (B) C: Edwy and Egilva, An Historical Romance of the Tenth Century. London: C. Chapple, 1811,4 vols. </P><Table><TR><TD>181. </TD><TD>1811 </TD><TD>c: anon., Alidia and Cloridian; Or, the Offspring of Bertha. A Romance of Former </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Times. London: N. L. Pannier, 1811,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>182. </TD><TD>1811 </TD><TD>C: Anwyl, Edward Trevor, Reginald Trevor; or, The Welsh Loyalists; a Tale of the </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>17th cenJury. London: Newman, 1811,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>183. </TD><TD>1811 </TD><TD>C: anon., The Black Banner, Or, The Siege of Clagenfurth. A Romantic Tale. By the </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Author of the 'Baron de Falkenheim', 'Mystery upon Mystery', etc. London: AK. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Newman and Co., 1811,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>184. </TD><TD>1811 </TD><TD>C: anon., The mountain chief' or, the descendanJ of William Tell, the deliverer of </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Switzerland, London: Hughes, 1811,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>185. </TD><TD>1811 </TD><TD>Disraeli, Isaac, Despotism. (B) </TD></TR><TR><TD>186. </TD><TD>1811 </TD><TD>C: anon., Gotha, or Memoirs of the Wurtzburg Family. Founded on Facts. London: C. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Chapple, 1811,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>187. </TD><TD>1811 </TD><TD>Liddiard, R.S. Anna, The Sgelaighe. (B) </TD></TR><TR><TD>188. </TD><TD>1811 </TD><TD>Mitchell, Isaac, Alonzo and Melissa (B) </TD></TR><TR><TD>189. </TD><TD>1811 </TD><TD>C: anon., Rosali; or, the Castle ofMontalbretti. London: Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orme </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>and Brown, 1811,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>190. </TD><TD>1811 </TD><TD>C: Smith, &lt;Catherine&gt;, The Caledonian Bandit; or The Heir of Duncaethal. A </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Romance ofthe Thirteenth Century. London: AK. Newman and Co., 1811,2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>191. </TD><TD>1811 </TD><TD>C: Wigley, &lt;Sarah&gt;, Glencarron: A Scottish Tale. London: Henry Colburn, 1811, 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>192. </TD><TD>1812 </TD><TD>Mrs. Byron, The Borderers. (B) C: &lt;Byron, Elizabeth&gt;, The Borderers. An Historical </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Romance, Illustrative of the Manners of the FourteenJh CenJury. London: A.K. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Newman and Co., 1812,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>193. </TD><TD>1812 </TD><TD>C: Hatton, Anne, Sicilian Mysteries, or the fortress del Vecchio London: Colburn, 1812, </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>5 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>194. </TD><TD>1812 </TD><TD>C: Helme, Elizabeth, Magdalen; or, The PemtenJ of Godstow. An Historical Novel. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Brentford: P. Norbury, 1812,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>195. </TD><TD>1812 </TD><TD>Macnei1&lt;!&gt;, Hector, The Scotish AdvenJurers. (B) C: MacNeill, Hector, The Scottish </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>AdvenJurers, or, The Way to Rise: A Historical Tale. Edinburgh: William Blackwood, </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>1812, 2nd ed. with alterations, 2 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>196. </TD><TD>1812 </TD><TD>C: anon., Old Times and New,' or, Sir Lionel and his Protegee. A Novel. London: </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Newman, 1812,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>197. </TD><TD>1812 </TD><TD>C: &lt;Radcliffe, Mary Anne&gt;, Ida of Austria; or, the Knights of the Holy Cross. A </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Romance by the Author of 'Manfrone'. London: Earle, Taylor and Co., 1812,3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>198. </TD><TD>1812 </TD><TD>C: Stuart, Augusta Amelia, Cava of Toledo; or, the Gothic Princess. A Romance. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>London: AX. Newman and Co., 1812,5 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>199. </TD><TD>1812 </TD><TD>West, Jane, The Loyalists. (B) C: The Loyalists: An Historical Novel. London: </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orme and Brown, 1812, 2nd ed., 3 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>200. </TD><TD>1812 </TD><TD>C: anon., Yamboo; or, the North American Slave. London: Lane, 1812,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>201. </TD><TD>1813 </TD><TD>C: Brewer, kames&gt; N&lt;orris&gt;, Sir Ferdinand of England, A Romance. London: A.K. </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>Newman, 1813,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>202. </TD><TD>1813 </TD><TD>C: Brewer, James Norris, Sir Gilbert Easterling, A Story, supposed to have been </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>written by himself about the year 1598. London: AK. Newman, 1813,4 vols. </TD></TR><TR><TD>203. </TD><TD>1813 </TD><TD>C: &lt;Brooke, Henry&gt;, The History of Henry, Earl ofMoreland. London: Blanshard &lt;eL </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>al.&gt;, 1813, 4th ed., 2 vols. </TD></TR></Table><P>204. 	1813 C: Hitchener, William H., The Towers ofRavenswold, or Days ofIronside. A Romance. London: C. Chapple, 1813,2 vols. cf. (B) 1814 </P><L><LI><LI_Label>205. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1813 Houghton, Mary, The Border Chieftains. (B) C: The Border Chieftains; or, Love and Chivalry; A Novel. London: G. and S. Robinson, 1813,3 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>206. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1813 C: anonym &lt;Phibbs, Mary&gt;, The Lady of Martendyke. An historical Tale of the Fifteenth Century. By a Lady. London: Colburn, 1813,4 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>207. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1813 C: Ward, Catherine George, My Native Land,' or, the Test of Heroism. London: Newman, 1813. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>208. </LI_Label><LI_Title>1814 	Hitchener, William Henry, The Towers ofRavenswold. (B) cf. (C) 1813 </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>209. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1814 C: O'Keeffe, Adelaide, Zenobia, Queen of Palmyra; A Narrative Founded on History. London: J. Dennett, F.C. and 1. Rivington, 1814,2 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>210. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1814 Roche, Regina Maria. Trecothic Bower. (B) C: Trecothic Bower; or, The Lady of the West Country. A Tale. London: AX. Newman and Co., 1814,2 vols. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>211. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>1814 West, Jane, Alicia de Lacy. (B) C: Alicia de Lacy, An Historical Romance. London: Longman, Rees, Hurst, Orme and Brown, 1814,4 vols. </LI_Title></LI></L></TaggedPDF-doc>